ALI SANAKNAKI

COMPUTER SCIENTIST SANAKNAKI.COM



PROFILE

In search to gain work experience in my field of study, to be placed in a position that will give me the opportunity to implement and enhance my skills gained from my university courses, and to learn how to function and work in a group to meet a specific goal.



CONTACT ME



(613) 809-0884



asana085@uottawa.ca



2743 Pimlico Crescent, Ottawa, ON **K1T2A7**



PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Computer Skills

Java - Intermediate HTML5, CSS, JS - Experienced C++ - Beginner FramerJS - Experienced

Sketch - **Experienced** Photoshop - Experienced

Language Skills

English - Intermediate French - Experienced Arabic - Experienced

Social Skills

Great at communicating with others regarding testing and errors with projects, can give clear ideas and explanations to features with proper explanation. Open-minded to criticism or ideas from peers or coworkers.



GET IN TOUCH



LINKEDIN.COM/IN/ALISANAKNAKI



GITHUB.COM/SANAKNAKI



TWITTER.COM/THEGOOGLEINTERN



WORK EXPERIENCE =

JUNIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

SpottedU Software Inc.

July 2015 - April 2016

Assisted in stress testing, bug fixing, joined in group meetings to plan feature designing and implementation for the website. Using HTML, multiple CSS frameworks (including Bootstrap) and basic Javascript.

SOCIAL MEDIA TEAM LEAD

SpottedU Software Inc.

July 2015 - April 2016

Advertised the new Social Network platform using Facebooks advertising tools, as well as updating the developer Medium blog for readers describing the latest update and future features, utilized Buffer to queue posts, created advertising graphics for Twitter and Instagram.

WEB CONTENT SPECIALIST

Environment and Climate Change Canada

June 2016 - August 2016

Created and updated web pages for ECCC's MetPlus website using HTML and utilizing CSS classes under the WET4 framework, graphics manipulation, and aided in QA testing of future features.



EDUCATION =

UNIVERSITY OF OTTAWA (2014-2018)

BSc Honours with Specialization in Computer Science

Currently pursuing a degree in Computer Science in order to graduate and enter a field of Software/Web Development.

ST. FRANCIS XAVIER HIGH SCHOOL (2010-2015)

Graduate

Graduated in July of 2015, also received bilingual diploma (French).



AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

ACADEMIC EXCELLENCE IN COMPUTER PROGRAMMING

This award was given to the student with the highest final grade in the class of Computer Programming (C++).

DIPLOMA FOR BLACK BELT ACHIEVEMENT IN TAEKWONDO

Diploma given to those who have achieved Black belt in Taekwondo, earning low level mastery in the art.